Hannah is excited to be going to college.
(هانا) متحمسة جدا كونها ذاهبة إلى الجامعة.
She couldn't wait to get out of her parents' house,
إذ أنها لم تستطع الانتظار للخروج من منزل والديها،
to prove to them that she's an adult,
ولتثبت لهم أنها ما عادت فتاة صغيرة،
and to prove to her new friends that she belongs.
ولتثبت أيضا لأصدقائها بأنها تنتمي لهم.
She heads to a campus party
توجهت إلى حفلة أقيمت في الجامعة
where she sees a guy that she has a crush on.
حيث رأت شابا يعجبها.
Let's call him Mike.
لنطلق عليه اسم (مايك).
The next day, Hannah wakes up with a pounding headache.
في اليوم التالي، استيقظت (هانا) وهي تعاني ألم شديد في رأسها.
She can only remember the night in flashes.
لا تستطيع تذكر سوى ومضات من ليلة البارحة.
But what she does remember is
ولكن الشيء الذي تستطيع تتذكره بوضوح
throwing up in the hall outside Mike's room
هو تقيؤها في الممر خارج غرفة (مايك)
and staring at the wall silently while he was inside her,
وتحديقها بصمت في الجدار بينما كان يمارس الجنس معها.
wanting it to stop,
راجيةً أن يتوقف ذلك.
then shakily stumbling home.
وبعد ذلك عادت إلى المنزل مرتجفة ومتعثرة.
She doesn't feel good about what happened,
هي لا تشعر بالرضا حيال ما حدث،
but she thinks, "Maybe this is just what sex in college is?"
ولكنها اعتقدت "على الأرجح أن هذه طبيعة الجنس في الجامعة"
One in five women and one in 13 men will be sexually assaulted
واحدة من أصل خمسة نساء وواحد من أصل ثلاثة عشر رجلاً سيتم الاعتداء عليهم جنسيا
at some point during their college career in the United States.
في مرحلة ما من حياتهم الجامعية في الولايات المتحدة الأمريكية.
Less than 10 percent will ever report their assault to their school
أقل من عشره في المئة سيبلغون كليتهم عن تعرضهم للإعتداء الجنسي
or to the police.
أو الشرطة.
And those who do, on average, wait 11 months to make the report.
والذين سيبلغون، ينتظرون 11 شهرا في المتوسط.
Hannah initially just feels like dealing with what happened on her own.
في البداية شعرت (هانا) أن عليها التعامل مع ما حدث بمفردها فقط،
But when she sees Mike taking girls home from parties,
لكن عند رؤيتها لـ(مايك) وهو يقود فتيات من الحفل إلى غرفته،
she's worried about them.
بدأت تقلق لأجلهن.
After graduation, Hannah learns
بعد التخرج، اكتشفت (هانا)
that she was one of five women who Mike did the exact same thing to.
أنها واحدة من أصل خمسة من نساء قام (مايك) بفعل الشيء ذاته لهن.
And this is not an unlikely scenario
وهذا احتمال وارد،
because 90 percent of sexual assaults
لأن تسعين في المئة من الإعتداءات الجنسية
are committed by repeat offenders.
يرتكبها معتدون يكررون فعلتهم.
But with such low reporting rates,
ولكن مع معدلات الإبلاغ المنخفضة،
it's fairly unlikely that even repeat perpetrators will be reported,
فإنه من غير المحتمل أن يتم الإبلاغ عن الجناة الذين يكررون فعلتهم،
much less anything happen if they are.
فما بالكم أن يعاقبوا إن أُبلغ عنهم.
In fact, only six percent of assaults reported to the police
في الواقع، ستة في المئة فقط من الإعتداءات والتي يتم إبلاغ الشرطة عنها
end with the assailant spending a single day in prison.
تنتهي بقضاء المعتدي ليوم واحد فقط في السجن.
Meaning, there's a 99 percent chance that they'll get away with it.
وهذا يعني أن فرصة النجاة من فعلتهم تقدر بنسبة ٩٩ في المئة.
This means there's practically no deterrent to assault
هذا يعني وبمفهوم عملي بأنه لا يوجد رادع للإعتداء
in the United States.
في الولايات المتحدة الأمريكية.
Now, I'm an infectious disease epidemiologist by training.
الآن، أنا أخصائية في الأوبئة والأمراض المعدية من خلال التدريب.
I'm interested in systems and networks
وأنا مهتمة بمجال الأنظمة والشبكات
and where we can concentrate our resources to do the most good.
حيث يمكننا تركيز مواردنا للقيام بعمل الأمور ذات المنفعة.
So this, to me, is a tragic but a solvable problem.
الإعتداء الجنسي، وبالنسبة لي، مشكلة مأساوية ولكنها قابلة للحل.
So when the issue of campus assault started hitting the news a few years ago,
عندما تصدرت قضية الإعتداء في الحرم الجامعي عناوين الأخبار منذ بضعة سنوات،
it felt like a unique opportunity to make a change.
شعرت وكأنها فرصة فريدة من نوعها لإحداث تغيير.
And so we did.
وهذا ما فعلناه بالضبط.
We started by talking to college survivors.
بدأنا بمخاطبة الناجين من الاعتداءات الجنسية في الجامعات.
And what they wish they'd had in college is pretty simple;
والشيء الذي تمنوا وجوده في الجامعة آنذاك هو شيء بسيط جداً.
they wanted a website,
أرادوا موقعاً على شبكة الانترنت،
one they could use at the time and place
موقعاً يمكنهم استخدامه في المكان والزمان
that felt safest to them
الذي اعتبروه الأكتر أمانا.
with clearly written information about their reporting options,
وبوجود معلومات مكتوبة وبشكل واضح حول خيارات وكيفية الإبلاغ،
with the ability to electronically report their assault,
مع القدرة على الإبلاغ بالإعتداء إلكترونياً
rather than having the first step
بدلاً من أن تكون الخطوة الأولى
to go in and talk to someone who may or may not believe them.
هي الذهاب والتحدث إلى شخص قد أو قد لا يصدق ما يقولون.
With the option to create a secure, timestamped document
مع خيار لإنشاء وثيقة مؤمنة، مختومة بالوقت والتاريخ
of what happened to them,
عن ما حصل لهم،
preserving evidence even if they don't want to report yet.
وحفظ الأدلة على الأقل حتى ومع عدم رغبتهم حينها في تقديم البلاغ.
And lastly, and perhaps most critically,
وأخيراً، ولربما النقطة الأهم
with the ability to report their assault
هي قدرتهم على الإبلاغ عن الاعتداء
only if someone else reported the same assailant.
فقط في حال تم الإبلاغ عن نفس الجاني من قبل شخص آخر.
You see, knowing that you weren't the only one changes everything.
كونك على علم بأنك لم تكن الضحية الوحيدة يغير كل شيء.
It changes the way you frame your own experience,
يقوم بتغيير النظرة أو الحالة النفسية حول الاعتداء.
it changes the way you think about your perpetrator,
ويقوم بتغيير الإعتقاد أو نمط التفكير حول المعتدي.
it means that if you do come forward,
وهذا يعني أنك إذا قمت بالإبلاغ
you'll have someone else's back and they'll have yours.
ستجد من يساندك و تسانده.
We created a website that actually does this
قمنا بإنشاء موقع إلكتروني يقوم بالفعل بهذا الإجراء
and we launched it [...] in August,
وقمنا بإطلاقه منذ شهرين وكان ذلك في أغسطس/آب
on two college campuses.
في اثنين من الجامعات.
And we included a unique matching system
وقمنا أيضا بإضافة نظام مطابقة فريد من نوعه
where if Mike's first victim had come forward,
إذ في حال قامت الضحية الأولى لـ(مايك) بالإبلاغ عنه
saved her record, entered into the matching system
وقامت بحفظ بلاغها، والذي تمت إضافته إلى النظام
and named Mike,
باسم (مايك)،
and Mike's second victim had done the same thing
وقامت ضحية (مايك) الثانية بعمل ما قامت به الاولى
a few months later,
بعد شهور قليلة،
they would have matched
سيحدث التطابق بين حالتيهما
and the verified contact information of both survivors
ومع وجود معلومات الاتصال الصحيحة والمثبتة لكلا الضحيتين
would have been sent to the authorities at the same time
كان ليتم إرسال هذه المعلومات للسلطات المعنية في نفس الوقت
for investigation and follow up.
للتحقيق والمتابعة.
If a system like this had existed for Hannah and her peers,
إذا وجد مثل هذا النظام لـ(هانا) وأقرانها،
it's more likely that they would have reported,
كن على الأرجح سيرفعن بلاغا.
that they would have been believed,
وكان سيتم حينها تصديقهن،
and that Mike would have been kicked off campus,
وكان أيضاً سيتم حينها طرد (مايك) من الجامعة.
gone to jail, or at least gotten the help that he needed.
أن يحكم عليه بالسجن، أو على الأقل حصل على المساعدة التي يحتاجها.
And if we were able to stop repeat offenders like Mike
وإذا كان بإمكاننا إيقاف المعتدين المكررين لفعلتهم على غرار (مايك)
after just their second assault following a match,
حال إعتدائهم للمرة الثانية، وفور المطابقة،
survivors like Hannah would never even be assaulted
لم يكن ليُعتدى على الناجين على غرار (هانا)
in the first place.
من أصله.
We could prevent 59 percent of sexual assaults
لكان باستطاعتنا منع ما يقارب ٥٩ في المئة من الإعتداءات الجنسية
just by stopping repeat perpetrators earlier on.
فقط من خلال إيقاف المعتدين المكررين لفعلتهم في وقت أبكر.
And because we're creating a real deterrent to assault,
ولأننا بصدد إنشاء رادع حقيقي للاعتداء،
for perhaps the first time,
ربما للمرة الأولى،
maybe the Mikes of the world would never even try to assault anyone.
حينها لن يقوم اشباه (مايك) حول العالم حتى بمحاولة الاعتداء على أي شخص.
The type of system I'm describing,
نوع النظام الذي أقوم بوصفه،
the type of system that survivors want
هو النوع الذي يريده الناجون من الإعتداءات الجنسية
is a type of information escrow,
هو النوع الذي يقوم بضمان سلامة وصحة المعلومات،
meaning an entity that holds on to information for you
وهو النظام الذي يقوم بحفظ المعلومات بالنيابة عنك
and only releases it to a third party
و لا يعطيها لطرف ثالث
when certain pre-agreed upon conditions are met,
إلا في حال تم استيفاء الشروط والتي تم الاتفاق عليها مسبقا،
such as a match.
كالتطابق على سبيل المثال.
The application that we built is for college campuses.
التطبيق الذي قمنا بإنشائه هو للجامعات.
But the same type of system could be used in the military
ولكن يمكن استخدام نفس هذا النوع من الأنظمة في الجيش
or even the workplace.
أو حتى في بيئة العمل.
We don't have to live in a world
ليس علينا العيش في عالم
where 99 percent of rapists get away with it.
حيث ينجو فيه ما يقارب ٩٩ في المئة من مرتكبي جرائم الإغتصاب من العقاب.
We can create one
نستطيع إنشاء عالم،
where those who do wrong are held accountable,
حيث يخضع فيه مرتكبو الأخطاء للعقوبة،
where survivors get the support and justice they deserve,
وحيث يحصل الناجون على الدعم والعدالة التي يستحقونها،
where the authorities get the information they need,
وحيث تحصل السلطات على المعلومات التي تحتاج إليها،
and where there's a real deterrent
وحيث يوجد رادع حقيقي
to violating the rights of another human being.
لإنتهاك حقوق إنسان آخر.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)